A Guide to the Karin Rühle Architectural Papers, 1991-1995
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Karin Rühle Architectural Papers, 1991-1995
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-016
8 boxes, 5 oversize; 34.5 cu. ft.
The collection currently only contains materials relating to one project, Projekt 1.10, Gartenstadt Jahnstrasse/Dahlwitz Hoppegarten, often abbreviated "Jahnstr," from 1992-1995.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Karin Rühle Architectural Papers were donated to Special Collections in the summer of 2000.
Biographical Information
No biographical information.
Scope and Content
The collection currently only contains materials relating to one project, Projekt 1.10, Gartenstadt Jahnstrasse/Dahlwitz Hoppegarten, often abbreviated "Jahnstr," from 1992-1995. The materials for this project consist mainly of architectural drawings, originals and copies, with related images and three-dimensional models of several of the project's buildings.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Contents List
- Jahnstr. Details Haus 1,1.2 l + k, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Jahnstr. Details Haus A, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Jahnstr. Details Haus B/B.2, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Jahnstr. Details Haus C, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Jahnstr. Details Haus 2, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Jahnstr. Details Haus 3, Arbeitsmappe, Originale, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Liste der ziegelsturze und-formsteine, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Haus 1, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Haus 1.2, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Haus 2, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Haus 3, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Haus A,B,C, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Farb-konsept, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Jahnstrasse Hoppegarten Neubau Arbeitsmappe Ziegellistein (?): Sonstiges, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:8)
- Jahnstrasse Aussenraumplanung Lageplane, 1995. (Box-folder 3:1)
- HOP Broschure, Entwurf, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 3:2)
- HOP Details, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 3:3)
- HOP Skizzen, 1991-1992. (Box-folder 3:4)
- HOP Broschuren Details Bader/Kuchen, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 4:1)
- HOP Andere Planungen: "Gartenstadt Jahnstrasse Dahlwitz-Hoppegarten" by SIGGE (Arkkitehtitoimisto Sigge Ky), n.d. (Box-folder 4:2)
- HOP Andere Planungen: "Dahlwitz-Hoppegarten Stadtebaulicher Rahmenplan Ortskern Hoppegarten" by Architekten Borck, Boye, Schaefer, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 4:2)
- HOP Broschuren Entwurf, 1992. (Box-folder 4:3)
- HOP 05.08.1993 Nachtrag Forderantrag, Drawings of H1, H1.2 l & k, H2, H3, HA, HB, HC, 1992-1995. (Box-folder 5:1)
- Untitled, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 5:2)
- HOP Broschuren, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 5:3)
- HOP Broschuren Vorentwurf, 1992. (Box-folder 5:4)
- (3) Model buildings, approximately 5.5" x 5.5" x 4.0", n.d. (Box 6)
- (1) Model buildings, approximately 5.25" x 17.5" x 5.25", n.d. (Box 6)
- (3) Model buildings, approximately 5.25" x 17.5" x 5.25", n.d. (Box 7)
- (1) Model buildings, approximately 5.25" x 23.0" x 4.5", n.d. (Box 7)
- Jahnstr. Modellfotos (I), n.d. (Box-folder 8:1)
- Jahnstr. Modellfotos (II), n.d. (Box-folder 8:2)
- Jahnstr. Modellfotos (III), n.d. (Box-folder 8:3)
- (Interior views of bathrooms and fixtures) Jahnstr. Projekt 1.10, n.d. (Box-folder 8:4)
- Jahnstr. Grundschnict vor Baubegirum (?), n.d. (Box-folder 8:5)
- Pflasles shassein, n.d. (Box-folder 8:6)
- HOP Broschuren Vorentwurf, 1992. (Box-folder 5:4)
- Negatives: Grundnicht unlier (?), n.d. (Box-folder 8:7)
- Negatives: Besprile (?), n.d. (Box-folder 8:8)
- Negatives: Vebainde (?), n.d. (Box-folder 8:9)
- Negatives: Aussernaulegern vebainde liegel (?), n.d. (Box-folder 8:10)
- Negatives: Unknown Subject, n.d. (Box-folder 8:11)
- H1–H1/A03.IV (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 1:1)
- H1/A04.I–H1/A11 (Drawings), 1992. (Oversize 1:2)
- H1/A12.I–H1/B11 (Drawings), 1992-1994. (Oversize 1:3)
- H1.2/A02.I–H1.2/A04.IV (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 1:4)
- H1.2/A05.Ia–H1.2I/A09.I (Drawings), 1992. (Oversize 1:5)
- H1.2k/A11–H1.2/A12.IV (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 1:6)
- H2/02–H2/A02.V (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 2:1)
- H2/A03.I–H2/A05.III (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 2:2)
- H2/A06–H2/A12.III (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 2:3)
- H2/B2–H2.2/A03.VI (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 2:4)
- H3/A02.I–H3/A03.III (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 3:1)
- H3/A04.I–H3/A07 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 3:2)
- H3/A08/10–H3/A12 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 3:3)
- H3/A13.I–H3/B11 (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 3:4)
- HA/A02–HA/A09 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 4:1)
- HA/A10–HA.2/A05 (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 4:2)
- HA.2/A06–HA.2/A11 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 4:3)
- HB/A02–HB/A10 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 4:4)
- HB/A11–HB.2/A05 (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 4:5)
- HB.2/A06–HB.2/A11 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 4:6)
- HC/A02–HC/A06 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 5:1)
- HC/A07–HC/A10 (Drawings), 1993. (Oversize 5:2)
- HC/A11–HC.2/A11 (Drawings), 1992-1993. (Oversize 5:3)
- HD/B8-B11–HD/B6-B7 (Drawings), 1992. (Oversize 5:4)
- Lageplans (Drawings), 1992-1994. (Oversize 5:5)
- 12.8-107a; Ausbauquerschnitte p + k (Drawings), 1992-1995. (Oversize 5:6)